<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="https://cincds.gov.mm/True%20News%20Information" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:og="http://ogp.me/ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:sioc="http://rdfs.org/sioc/ns#" xmlns:sioct="http://rdfs.org/sioc/types#" xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#">
  <channel>
    <title>Announcement</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/True%20News%20Information</link>
    <description></description>
    <language>en</language>
     <atom:link href="https://cincds.gov.mm/engAnnounce/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
    <title>Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services  Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace  (12th Waning of Thadingyut, 1382 ME)  (12 November, 2020)</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9793</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-1-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-1 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/statement%2013-11-2020.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/statement%2013-11-2020.jpg?itok=kmn-XErv&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republic of the Union of Myanmar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12th Waning of Thadingyut, 1382 ME)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(12 November, 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.       Statements on halting the military operations were issued in September and October 2020, and the Tatmadaw ceased its operations till the end of November 2020 for the successful holding of the 2020 multi-party democracy general election of the Republic of the Union of Myanmar, the effectiveness of COVID-19 prevention and containment undertakings, and the effective and successful realization of the Part 3 of the Union Accord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.       Moreover, the statement on the attitude towards the EAOs in respect of the 2020 multi-party democracy general election was released on 2 November 2020 before the election day; and the statement on the establishment of the peace talks committee of the Tatmadaw and its functions with the aim of successfully restoring the eternal peace was released on 9 November 2020 one day after the election day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.       ULA/AA released a statement on 12 November 2020 requesting the holding of a by-election in the areas in Rakhine State where the election could not be held before 31 December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.       The Tatmadaw has already expressed its serious stance on the freeness and fairness of the multiparty general election and on enabling all the eligible voters to cast votes at the respective constituencies. Hence, the Tatmadaw welcomes the statement of ULA/AA and assures utmost coordinated efforts to hold a by-election in the areas where the election has not been held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5.       In addition, the respective organizations are urged to make collective and coordinated efforts to hold a by-election in Mongkai Township of Shan State, soonest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services       &lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 06:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">9793 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9793#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace  (9th Waning of Thadingyut, 1382 ME)</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9764</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-2-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-2 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/news%2011-10-202.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/news%2011-10-202.jpg?itok=gpF_sA_r&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republic of the Union of Myanmar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(9th Waning of Thadingyut, 1382 ME)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(9 November, 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.         The fourth session of the Union Peace Conference-21st Century Panglong was held from 19 to 21 August 2020. The past conferences including the most recent conference approved three parts of the Union Accord and 54 points of agreement. Although it was necessary to continue talks for these agreements and remaining facts involved in the Nationwide Ceasefire Agreement, it was designed to temporarily postpone the continuation of peace talks because of outbreak of COVID-19 and process of holding the 2020 multi-party democracy general election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.         As the 2020 multi-party democracy general election has been successfully held, COVID-19 pandemic can be controlled to some degree, and achieving success of eternal peace is a must for the State, it is necessary to continue peace talks as quickly as possible with the armed organizations which are signatories to the Nationwide Ceasefire Agreement and the ethnic armed organizations which are still holding talks to sign the NCA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.         As such, the Peace Talks Committee of the Tatmadaw was formed with following persons in order to continue talks with the ethnic armed organizations if necessary for successfully restoring the eternal peace till the end of process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            (a)       Lieutenant-General Yar Pyae                     Chairman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            (b)       Lieutenant-General Tun Tun Naung           member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            (c)       Lieutenant-General Tin Maung Win           member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            (d)       Lieutenant-General Min Naung                  member&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;            (e)       Lieutenant-General Aung Lin Dway          Secretary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.         The information was released that the Peace Talks Committee of the Tatmadaw must continue talks with the Nationwide Ceasefire Agreement (NCA) signatory ethnic armed organizations for further strengthening of peace in accord with the NCA, must continue peace talks with non-signatory ethnic armed organizations until they have signed the NCA and must hold necessary talks to accomplish the goal of restoring eternal peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 02:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">9764 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9764#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services  Statement on attitude for EAOs related to election  (2nd Waning of Thadingyut, 1382 ME)</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9658</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-3-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-3 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/ook%203-11-2020.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/ook%203-11-2020.jpg?itok=i_u5jmU8&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republic of the Union of Myanmar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement on attitude for EAOs related to election&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; Waning of Thadingyut, 1382 ME)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2 November, 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;Successive governments including Tatmadaw government strived for restoring eternal peace after ceasing ethnics’ armed conflicts based on political, racial and religious affairs in the areas of Myanmar where national races reside. Ceasing of armed conflicts depends on endeavours of governments in successive eras as well as on keenness of ethnic armed organizations (EAOs) to secure peace. In the term of the government which initiated democracy in Myanmar, eight ethnic armed organizations signed the Nationwide Ceasefire Agreement (NCA) and the Union Peace Conference could be convened. In the term of present government, two more ethnic armed organizations signed the NCA and the conference was held with the title of Union Peace Conference: 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Century Panglong. However, it can be seen that the conference could not bring remarkable success to the peace yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;At the ceremony to mark the third anniversary of the NCA, the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services pledged to trust the eternal peace to the people in 2020. But, only when, EAOs are keen to restore the eternal peace, will they secure the genuine peace. In the actual situation, it was found that some EAOs built their strengths as acts to delay the peace process. Their acts cause not only delay to the peace process but also loss of the freedom of voting rights which is a chance to the local people in the multi-party democracy general election to be held on 8 November 2020. Although nine townships could not hold the election in the past, the Union Election Commission announced that current election cannot be held in 15 townships and village-tracts of some townships. Disturbance and pressure of some armed organizations cause delay to the progress of peace process which plays a key role in democratization as well as loss of voting rights to ethnic people which are important for democracy in some areas. Moreover, political parties cannot hold canvassing with loss of democracy rights. As administrators cannot be appointed and relevant election sub-commissions cannot be formed in some townships and villages dominated by ethnic armed organizations, situations in these areas are difficult to hold the free and fair election. However, the Tatmadaw expects that by-elections might be held in the near future in secure and smooth process in the areas where the election could not be held on 8 November 2020 due to various reasons. To be able to do so, ethnic armed organizations need to avoid positioning and movements in the areas not related to them and to soonest leave these areas if they have been there for various reasons. As such, the Tatmadaw invited and urged the ethnic armed organizations not to threat local ethnic people and to perform their tasks in accord with the NCA route for holding the free and fair election, rights for political parties to canvass and carry out peace process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 01:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">9658 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9658#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Announcement of stance on situation of the pre-2020 multiparty democracy general election  (2nd Waning of Thadingyut, 1382 ME)</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9657</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-4-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-4 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/uuuk%203-11-202001.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/uuuk%203-11-202001.jpg?itok=iVNVwWYe&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republic of the Union of Myanmar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Announcement of stance on situation of the pre-2020 multiparty democracy general election&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2&lt;sup&gt;nd&lt;/sup&gt; Waning of Thadingyut, 1382 ME)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(2 November, 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;1. The Tatmadaw had played the leading role in conducting implementations and reforms for the adoption of the multiparty democracy, aspired by the people, in the Republic of the Union of Myanmar. During the 2010 multiparty democracy general election, the Union Election Commission, chaired by U Thein Soe was formed, and a free and fair multiparty democracy general election could be held. Likewise, during the 2015 multiparty democracy general election, the Union Election Commission, chaired by U Tin Aye was formed under the announcement No. 5/2011 of the President Office issued on 30 March 2011, and a free and fair multiparty democracy general election could be successfully held. As for the 2020 multiparty democracy general election, the Union Election Commission, chaired by U Hla Thein was formed, under the announcement No. 4/2016 of the President Office issued on 30 March 2016. The election commissions got an average time span of 1,684 days (four years, seven months and nine days), and it is found that the time is enough for holding a free and fair election and the preparations for ensuring order at the election. The Union Election Commission Office has gained much experience from the previous two multiparty democracy general elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;2. The sections from 398 to 403 of the Constitution clearly state the formation of the UEC, duties, impeachment and resolutions and functions. Under the provisions of the Section 399 it is clearly stated, “prescribing rules relating to elections or political parties in accord with the provisions of this Constitution, and procedures, directives, so forth, accord with the relevant laws.” The provisions state the issuance of rules, procedures and directives relating to elections in accord with the Constitution and the relevant laws. The enactment or amendment of laws and rules for the multiparty democracy general election were conducted continuously during the period from 2010 to 2019. As for the Union Election Commission, there is a legal point of view that the issuance of procedures, notifications, orders and directives must be based on the existing laws. Currently, persons who have the pre-voting rights are casting their advance votes for the 2020 multiparty democracy general election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;3. But according to official announcements of political parties and their statements to the media and the media news reports, there is widespread violation of the laws and procedures of the pre-voting process, and the information about the situation of the remote areas with poor transport is so hard to receive. Although the Union Election Commission had over four years of preparation time for the 2020 election, there is much weakness even in arranging envelopes for votes and ballot boxes. Although provisions in connection with the pre-votes have already been stipulated in election laws and rules of the respective Hluttaws, there are announcements that are above the existing laws and the statements issued under the pretext of protecting the of voting rights, but that goes beyond the existing laws. So, there appear public doubts. The Republic of the Union of Myanmar conducted a nation-wide census in 2014, and has an annual estimated census in the following years. An estimated number of voters can be received from those census results. However, it is found that the Union Election Commission faced difficulties in counting the number of eligible voters and made a lot of careless mistakes in issuing the voter lists. Additionally, disputes in connection with the pre-voting are surfacing every day at present. The Republic of the Union of Myanmar has been in the process of stage by stage transition to multiparty democracy since the time of the Tatmadaw Government, and could hold the election which is the lifeblood of the multiparty democracy in 2010 and 2015 freely and fairly. Especially, local and foreign observers and organizations unanimously acknowledged the freeness and fairness of the 2015 election. Based on the experiences of the 2010 and 2015 elections, the coming 2020 election should have greater freeness and fairness. But weakness and deficiencies which were never seen in the previous elections are appearing now. They can have adverse impacts on the image of the election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;4. Although the Union Election Commission is an independent body, it was formed by the President. As the commission is formed under Sub-section (A) of Section (398) of the Constitution, Sub-section (E) of Section (9) of the Union Government Law and Section (3) of the Union Election Commission Law, the Union Government is responsible for the commission and the commission reports to the former.  Therefore, criticisms about the freeness and fairness of election is rather directed not at the commission but at the government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;5. As the government of the Republic of the Union of Myanmar is an administration that has taken state duties through the free and fair multi-party democracy election in 2015, it is expected that efforts will be made to hold the general election in 2020 in accordance with wishes of the people and international community. However, it is doubtful that the activities of the commission, which was formed by the government, are heading to that end. It is also found that negative outcomes were caused by the loose supervision and actions of the commission to enforce political parties to observe the rules and regulations for election campaigns that have started since 8 August 2020 and the health standard operation procedure (SOP) issued on 6 September by the Ministry of Health and Sports. The government has the complete responsibility for all the intentional and unintentional mistakes of the commission at its different levels. It is a political process that reflects the fulfilment of its responsibilities of a government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;6. COVID-19, the pandemic that started in March 2020 in Myanmar is still going on with the increased momentum. The pandemic has impacts on the socioeconomic lives of the people and the impacts are getting more and more severe. However, it is found that the public, with the understanding that the upcoming election is important for their socioeconomic lives, exerting efforts to cast their votes. The public expects that the upcoming election will bring about a positive change for them. It is an imperative that the upcoming election is free and fair in accordance with the will of the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;7. Under the check and balance system between the Union Government and the UEC, the incumbent government is required to conduct systematic and correct supervision on the performance of duties by the commission to hold free and fair elections with the aim of fulfilling the wish of the people, who expect positive changes under the stress of the pandemic. In the international community, elections usually reflect the integrity and correctness of governments. Therefore, it is the responsibility of the UEC and the Union Government, which are mutually responsible, to make the upcoming election of the Republic of the Union of Myanmar a free and fair one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 01:48:32 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">9657 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9657#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>False news about gunfire hit ICRC supply vessel spreading on social media; it was AA terrorists’ motor schooner </title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9595</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-5-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-5 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/icrc%20news%2029-10-2020%20%282%29.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/icrc%20news%2029-10-2020%20%282%29.jpg?itok=NJLau1Vz&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-2 odd last&quot; style=&quot;display:none;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/icrc%20news%2029-10-2020%20%281%29.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-2 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/icrc%20news%2029-10-2020%20%281%29.jpg?itok=r_h_K71u&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;ul id=&quot;field-slideshow-5-pager&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-pager slides-2&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-thumbnail field-slideshow-thumbnail-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/thumbnail/public/icrc%20news%2029-10-2020%20%282%29.jpg?itok=TuxmP-iW&quot; width=&quot;77&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-thumbnail field-slideshow-thumbnail-2 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/thumbnail/public/icrc%20news%2029-10-2020%20%281%29.jpg?itok=SNUuTvtR&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; height=&quot;56&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
  

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;False news about gunfire hit ICRC supply vessel spreading on social media; it was AA terrorists’ motor schooner &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;Nay Pyi Taw  October  28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;Some of the social media network pages were posting false news saying a food supply vessel of International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) caught fire and was destroyed on Meyu River near Kanbyin Village, Yathedaung Township, Rakhine State, this afternoon as it was hit by Tatmadaw fire.&lt;br /&gt;
But the truth is that it was an AA terrorists’ vessel that fired heavy and small weapons at three Tatmadaw naval vessels serving administrative duties in Meyu River. When the Tatmadaw vessels arrived at the place near Mingyun about 2,000 metres south of Aungzeya Village while on their way from Aungzeya Village to Yathedaung this morning, AA terrorists on board a 40 feet long and about 17 feet wide motor schooner coming at high speed from the west bank of the river shot at them with small arms and heavy weapons. And when the security forces on board the Tatmadaw vessels fired back, the terrorists’ motor schooner caught fire and drifted down the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;When contact was made with ICRC officers to inquire about the incident, they said that it was not theirs; that all humanitarian aid programmes were being carried out only after informing the relevant coordination committee in advance; and that security forces were providing cooperation and all necessary assistance. The news report is issued for the people to know the truth about the incident as false information saying that an ICRC food supply vessel was hit by weapon fire was spreading on the social media network.                                  &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 02:37:04 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">9595 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9595#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace (13th Waxing of Tawthalin, 1382 ME) (29 September, 2020)</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9213</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-6-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-6 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/statement%2030-9-2020.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/statement%2030-9-2020.png?itok=XPw0Vqn0&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republic of the Union of Myanmar&lt;br /&gt;
Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;br /&gt;
Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace&lt;br /&gt;
(13th Waxing of Tawthalin, 1382 ME)&lt;br /&gt;
(29 September, 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;1.    The Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services issued a statement that the Tatmadaw has extended the period of ceasefire in the areas from 1 to 30 September 2020 except the areas of the terrorist organizations declared by the government meeting the international standard, with the aim of carrying out more effective, rapid prevention, control and treatment of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19), restoring eternal peace in Myanmar and supporting the Appeal for Global Ceasefire of United Nations Secretary-General Antonio Guterres. &lt;br /&gt;
2.    Currently, as high rate of infection and deaths happen across the nation during the second wave of COVID-19, prevention, control and treatment of COVID-19 is being accelerated in the entire nation. The Myanmar Tatmadaw also actively participates in the tasks with might and main for serving the State and national interests.&lt;br /&gt;
3.    The information was released that the Tatmadaw will extend suspension of military movements in the areas from 1 to 31 October 2020 again except the areas of the terrorist organizations declared by the government meeting the international standard so as to accelerate momentum of prevention, control and treatment of COVID-19 and effectively and successfully implement eternal peace process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;
Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 02:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">9213 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9213#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Press Statement</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9044</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-7-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-7 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/pressstatements.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/pressstatements.jpg?itok=TFuhvh6K&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;Press Statement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;On 6 July 2020, it was announced that a court of inquiry led by Major-General Myat Kyaw had been established to investigate the events at the Chut Pyin and Maung Nu villages in Rakhine State in 2017.This investigation has advanced to such an extent that we can now announce that there will be a court-martial in this case, commencing&lt;br /&gt;
before the end of 2020. Allegations regarding Taung Bazar are included in the scope of the Maung Nu investigation announced on 6 July 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;Furthermore, we also announce that the analysis by the Office of the Judge Advocate General of the final report (with annexes) of the Independent Commission of Enquiry(ICOE) and other information has reached the point where the Office is investigating possible wider patterns of violations in the region of northern Rakhine in 2016-2017. Allegations regarding villages in the Maungdaw area are included in the scope of this wider investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;Tatmadaw True News Information Team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 02:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">9044 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/9044#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title> Republic of the Union of Myanmar Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/8814</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-8-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-8 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/25818200.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/25818200.jpg?itok=Vtxi1BHJ&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republic of the Union of Myanmar Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republic of the Union of Myanmar&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(6th Waxing of Wagaung, 1382 ME)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtecenter&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(24 August, 2020)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.        The Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services issued a statement on 9 May 2020 that the Tatmadaw put into effect for ceasefire in the areas from 10 May to 31 August 2020 except the areas of the terrorist organizations declared by the government meeting the international standard, with the aim of carrying out more effective and rapid prevention, control and treatment of Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) and restoring eternal peace in Myanmar on a wider scale and will effectively carry out continuous participation in prevention and control of COVID-19 with might and main as national cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.        As global countries are encountering world pandemic COVID-19, Secretary-General Antonio Guterres of the United Nations on 23 March 2020 urged all to stop armed conflicts happening throughout the world and issued the Appeal for Global Ceasefire of the UN Secretary-General. As part of supporting the Appeal for Global Ceasefire of the UN Secretary-General, the United Nations Security Council adopted a resolution on 1 July that all stakeholders involved in the armed conflicts were urged to implement the ceasefire at least 90 days with the aim of providing humanitarian aid during the COVID-19 period and to give a helping hand to responding to the COVID-19. Our country, being a member country of the United Nations, is responsible for abiding by international ethics and the resolution of the United Nations and is practising them similar to that of other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.        Moreover, the information was released that the Tatmadaw will continuously take preventive and control measures of COVID-19 with might and main as national duty and will extend suspension of military movements in the areas from 1 to 30 September 2020 except the areas of the terrorist organizations declared by the government meeting the international standard so as to carry out more effective and rapid undertakings of prevention and control of the disease and effectively and successfully implement the part-3 of the Nationwide Ceasefire Agreement signed in the fourth session of the Union Peace Conference - 21st Century Panglong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 01:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">8814 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/8814#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>  Tatmadaw True News Information Team meets media at press conference</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/8475</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-9-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-9 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/25-7-2020%20e%20%281%29.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/25-7-2020%20e%20%281%29.jpg?itok=SgzAuf5H&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Tatmadaw True News Information Team meets media at press conference&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Nay Pyi Taw July 25&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Brig-Gen Zaw Min Tun from the Tatmadaw True News Information Team met with media at the Defence Services Museum, here, this afternoon to hold the Tatmadaw press conference and replied to queries raised by media.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Before the press conference,officials from the Directorate of Medical Services of the Office of the Commander-in-Chief (Army) performed measuring of body temperature of those present at the press conference and systematically asked them in designated distance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;First, Brig-Gen Zaw Min Tun from the Tatmadaw True News Information Team explained undertakings of the Tatmadaw for Humanitarian Assistance and Disaster Relief-HADR, continuous training of Tatmadaw members in accord with the guidance of the Commanderin- Chief of Defence Services to have capabilities for responding to various dangers including natural disasters which may fall on the State and citizens in a short time similar to that of international armed forces, soonest carrying out of rescue and relief tasks to the scene of natural disasters without waiting for any order, and efforts of the Tatmadaw in forming the central committee chaired by the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services for effective prevention and rescue of natural disasters and giving a helping hand to the people,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;work committee and different committees at military command level, division level and regiment and unit levels.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;He clarified discipline breaking acts of ethnic armed organizations in five military command areas from 22 June to 21 July after the Tatmadaw has released the Statement on Ceasefire and Eternal Peace set from 10 May to 31 August 2020, seizures of narcotic drugs, and the meeting between the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services and the Ambassador of the People’s Republic of China to Myanmar at the parlour of Bayintnaung Villa in Nay Pyi Taw on 16 July to talk about cooperation between the two armed forces during the period of COVID-19, matters of peace process, peace and stability for northern area of Myanmar, security measures in  border region and cooperation in drug eradication and replied to queries raised by the media.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Also present at the press conference were 42 reporters from local news agencies, daily newspapers, journals, local TV broadcasting stations, local-based foreign news agencies, totalling 22.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 03:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">8475 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/8475#comments</comments>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Republic of the Union of Myanmar  Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services Statement on death and injuries caused by landslide in block of the gems  mining company near Whaykha Village, Hpakant Township, Kachin State (13th Waxing of First Waso</title>
    <link>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/8187</link>
    <description>&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-field-photos field-type-image field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot;&gt;&lt;div id=&quot;field-slideshow-10-wrapper&quot; class=&quot;field-slideshow-wrapper&quot;&gt;

  
  
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow field-slideshow-10 effect-fade timeout-4000 with-pager with-controls&quot; style=&quot;width:1100px; height:550px&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;field-slideshow-slide field-slideshow-slide-1 even first&quot;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/3-7-2020%281%292_0.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;field-slideshow-image field-slideshow-image-1 img-responsive img-responsive&quot; typeof=&quot;foaf:Image&quot; src=&quot;https://cincds.gov.mm/sites/default/files/styles/1100x550/public/3-7-2020%281%292_0.jpg?itok=dG38esCa&quot; width=&quot;1100&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;              &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-items&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;field-item even&quot; property=&quot;content:encoded&quot;&gt;&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Republic of the Union of Myanmar  Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services Statement on death and injuries caused by landslide in block of the gems mining company near Whaykha Village, Hpakant Township, Kachin State (13th Waxing of First Waso, 1382 ME) (2 July, 2020)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;1. The landslide in the block of the gems mining company near Whaykha Village of Hpakant Township in Kachin State left 123 persons dead and 31 persons injured&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;till 6 pm today. Tatmadaw members, administrative bodies, members of auxiliary fire brigade and social organizations are carrying out search and rescue tasks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;2. The Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services was deeply regretful for the event of losing many human lives, and the Tatmadaw, on its part, hereby released that it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;rtejustify&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;will continuously give a helping hand to necessary search and rescue tasks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size:12.0pt&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family:&amp;quot;Myanmar3&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;serif&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Office of the Commander-in-Chief of Defence Services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
     <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 02:58:26 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>cincdsmyanmar</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">8187 at https://cincds.gov.mm</guid>
 <comments>https://cincds.gov.mm/node/8187#comments</comments>
  </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
